Ned Schnurman Video Collection
Ned Schnurman Video Collection
1961-1995
Schnurman, Ned.
19.5 linear feet
video collection of the television producer of the PBS program Inside Story.
4100985
Biographical History
Ned Schnurman (1925-2004) was an American television producer. He was President and Senior Executive of The Press and the Public Project, Inc. and was producer for the Public Broadcasting Service television program, Inside Story.
Originally from Brooklyn, New York, Ned Schnurman attended New York University before embarking on a long and varied career in newspaper and television journalism. After breaking-in as a newspaper reporter and editor, Schnurman became News Director and Executive Producer for the public television station WNET, Channel 13, during the early 1960s (1962-1966), and then later produced special projects for National Educational Television (NET). Schnurman later worked as Assistant News Director and City Editor at WCBS-TV in New York during the early 1970s (1970-1973). In 1981, while serving as Senior Executive and President of The Press and the Public Project, Schnurman started a media criticism program for PBS, Inside Story, featuring Hodding Carter as anchor and comedians Bob Elliott and Ray Goulding ("Bob and Ray") as sometimes correspondents. The program ran for four years, and featured episodes analyzing journalistic ethics in coverage of the Atlanta child murders, events in El Salvador, U.S.-Soviet relations, the "Star Wars" missle defense initiative, health and medical reporting and other timely subjects. Perhaps the program is most noted in retrospect for the controversy surrounding the airing of the episode, "Vienam Op/Ed: An Inside Story Special" (1985), a Conservative "equal-time" rebuttal to the award winning WGBH produced documentary, Vietnam: A Television Hisotory (1983). Schnurman was awarded 6 Emmy's over the course of his career--two early in his career for producing the NET programs Your Dollar's Worth and The President's Farewell (on Lyndon B. Johnson)--and four for his work on Inside Story. Ned Schnurman died in 2004.
[sources consulted: Prial, Frank J. "Ned Schnurman, 78, Producer of Media Criticism Program" [obituary], 31 May 2004, The New York Times.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The vast bulk of the Ned Schnurman Video Collection consists of video tapes in VHS and Umatic formats collected for use in the production of the PBS series, Inside Story. The material includes clip reels of network news stories, historical film footage, excerpts taken from broadcast programs, and dubs of complete television programs and film documentaries. The material originates from a range of sources, including the major broadcast TV and cable networks (ABC, CBS, NBC, HBO, CNN, TBS, PBS), professional and private film production entities, and various local TV stations. Materials were collected in relation to the topics for the various episodes of Inside Story, and include substantial material related to the Vietnam War, U.S.-Soviet Relations, World War II (including Movietone newsreel footage), Modern athletes and athletics, the 1960s radical movement, Presidential press conferences, local news media coverage of historical events, and other topics. The collection also includes a few dubs of Inside Story episodes and clip reels/highlight reels of features from that program.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection remains in original order. For ease of reference, the inventory is presented in alphabetical order.
Related Material
has made a concerted effort over the years to ensure that its manuscript and rare books holdings complement each other. As a result, many of our manuscript collections are supported by books, pamphlets, serials and other items which are cataloged in the Rare Books Collection. Please be sure to search for these related materials.
Subject and Genre Headings
Radio, television, film; Popular culture; Schnurman, Ned.; Press and the Public Project.; Public Broadcasting Service (U.S.); Inside story (Television program); Documentary television programs.; History, Modern -- 20th century -- Pictorial works.; Television broadcasting of news -- United States.; Vietnam War, 1961-1975 -- Television and the war.; World War, 1939-1945 -- Motion pictures and the war.; Documentary film.; Television programs.; Videocassettes.; Television journalists.; Television producers and directors.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Access to video recordings requires advance notice to produce a working copy.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Ned Schnurman, 1999.
Inventory
- Video
  - 50 Years Ago Today (show tapes for the week of Sept 2-6 1941) [schnur_198], (VHS) (Box 12)
  - 50 Years Ago Today: Pearl Harbor Examined (Part 1 of 3) (Hunt for Pearl Harbor Files) [schnur_088], (Umatic) (Box 6)
  - 50 years Ago Today: Pearl Harbor Examined (Part 2 of 3) (Hunt for Pearl Harbor Files) [schnur_089], (Umatic) (Box 6)
  - 50 Years Ago Today: Pearl Harbor Examined (Panel Discussion) (Part 3 of 3) (Hunt for Pearl Harbor Files) [schnur_090], (Umatic) (Box 6)
  - 60 Minutes (CBS) 08/22/1982 [schnur_190], (Umatic) (Box 12)
  - 60 Minutes: Atlantic Charter (CBS) [schnur_049], (Umatic) (Box 4)
  - ABC Close-up: Near Armageddon 05/28/1981 [schnur_006], (Umatic) (Box 1)
  - ABC News 20/20 (1st broadcast) 06/26/1978 [schnur_003], (Umatic) (Box 1)
  - ABC News Our World: Gone with the Wind: the Making of a Classic [schnur_011], (Umatic) (Box 1)
  - ABC World News (Reasoner sign-off) 07/10/1978 [schnur_004], (Umatic) (Box 1)
  - Accuracy in Academia (Episode #410) (WNED) 03/19/1986 [schnur_013], (Umatic-SP) (Box 1)
  - Adam Smith's Money World: Can the Soviet Union Afford Star Wars? (Episode #221) 11/11/1985 [schnur_015], (Umatic) (Box 1)
  - Adam Smith's Money World: Star Wars (Episode #225) 02/17/1986 [schnur_016], (Umatic) (Box 1)
  - Afghanistan: Behind Russian Lines (TNT) [schnur_145], (Umatic) (Box 9)
  - Agnew Speech (CBS) [schnur_060], (Umatic) (Box 4)
  - Agnew Speech on TV news (1968), MLK funeral (1968), JFK Inaugural Address (1/1961) (CBS) [schnur_027], (Umatic) (Box 2)
  - All About TV: CBS Nightwatch (2/20/1983), All About TV: NBC Overnight (2/27/1983) (WNYC) [schnur_055], (Umatic) (Box 4)
  - AT&T Longline Satellites ("To Space and Back: Bell System Satellite Communications") (CBS) 05/15/1985 [schnur_028], (Umatic) (Box 2)
  - Bilder aus Amerika 06/08/1982 [schnur_189], (Umatic) (Box 12)
  - Breshnev's Funeral (CBS) 11/15/1982 [schnur_052], (Umatic) (Box 4)
  - Burning Nun (5/29/66) and Burning Monk (5/9/71) [ABC?] [schnur_002], (Umatic) (Box 1)
  - CBS Evening News ("Mideast fighting" 7/4/76, 11/10/79, 5/24/79, 8/30/79) [schnur_043], (Umatic) (Box 3)
  - CBS Evening News (4/26/76, 11/30/77 (Severeid), 3/6/81 (closing) [schnur_042], (Umatic) (Box 3)
  - CBS Evening News (Afghanistan Features 4/5-4/7/83) [schnur_056], (Umatic) (Box 4)
  - CBS Evening News 5/19/1965 (Dominican Republic) 05/19/1965 [schnur_035], (Umatic) (Box 3)
  - CBS Morning News 3/31/1981: Assassination Attempt Aftermath 03/31/1981 [schnur_048], (Umatic) (Box 3)
  - CBS Morning News 10/12/1973 ("Mideast fighting") 10/12/1973 [schnur_040], (Umatic) (Box 3)
  - CBS Morning News 3/31/1981: Assassination Attempt Aftermath (9-10AM) 03/31/1981 [schnur_047], (Umatic) (Box 3)
  - CBS Morning News: Interviews with Mike Wallace (1/21/1982), T. Turner (2/8/1983), Feshbach (2/25/1983) [schnur_053], (Umatic) (Box 4)
  - CBS Reports Walter Cronkite: Honor, Duty and a War called Vietnam 04/25/1985 [schnur_058], (Umatic) (Box 4)
  - CBS Reports ("Volga") 03/22/1983 [schnur_054], (Umatic) (Box 4)
  - CBS Reports 1/26/1995: In the Killing Fields of America 01/26/1995 [schnur_059], (VHS) (Box 4)
  - CBS Reports: Murder: Teenage Style [schnur_063], (Umatic) (Box 4)
  - CBS Reports: 1968 (Part I) [schnur_036], (Umatic) (Box 3)
  - CBS Reports: Moyer's "Poor" (People Like Us) 04/21/1982 [schnur_051], (Umatic) (Box 4)
  - CBS Reports: Murder: Teenage Style [schnur_062], (Umatic) (Box 4)
  - CBS Reports: The Business of Newspapers 07/14/1978 [schnur_044], (Umatic) (Box 3)
  - College: The Undergraduate Experience in America (Carnegie Foundation Colloquium) [schnur_018], (Umatic) (Box 2)
  - College: The Undergraduate Experience in America (Carnegie Foundation Colloquium) [schnur_017], (Umatic) (Box 2)
  - Confessions of an Undercover Cop (HBO) [schnur_083], (VHS) (Box 5)
  - Covering the Coverage (Part 1) (PBL) 05/22/1985 [schnur_130], (Umatic) (Box 8)
  - Covering the Coverage (Part 2) (PBL) [schnur_131], (Umatic) (Box 8)
  - Cuban Missile Crisis History (WTVJ) 05/15/1985 [schnur_178], (Umatic) (Box 11)
  - December 7th (Part I) [schnur_199], (Umatic) (Box 12)
  - December 7th (Part II) and Dai Toa News [schnur_200], (Umatic) (Box 13)
  - Democratic Party National Convention 8/27/1968 (CBS) 08/27/1968 [schnur_038], (Umatic) (Box 3)
  - Eisenhower Press Conference c.1956 (CBS) 05/09/1985 [schnur_023], (Umatic) (Box 2)
  - Election Special (Visnews) [schnur_185], (Umatic) (Box 12)
  - Exploding Cities (National Film Board of Canada) [schnur_117], (Umatic) (Box 7)
  - Eyeball to Eyeball: Dilemma in the Newsroom (1 of 2) (WNET) 01/20/1982 [schnur_067], (Umatic) (Box 5)
  - Fire Season (WNET) 02/23/1983 [schnur_134], (Umatic) (Box 9)
  - Firing Line: Higher Education has Failed Democracy (Alan Bloom) (Episode #164) [schnur_068], (Umatic) (Box 5)
  - Ford Speech 10/16/74 (CBS) 10/16/1974 [schnur_041], (Umatic) (Box 3)
  - Former Ambassadors to the Soviet Union (#1) 04/08/1984 [schnur_143], (Umatic) (Box 9)
  - Former Ambassadors to the Soviet Union (#2) [schnur_201], (Umatic) (Box 13)
  - Former Ambassadors to the Soviet Union (#3) [schnur_202], (Umatic) (Box 13)
  - Former Ambassadors of the Soviet Union (#4) [schnur_211], (Umatic) (Box 13)
  - Fredericks cont. (#90) (original) [schnur_203], (Umatic-SP) (Box 13)
  - From D-Day to the Rhine with Bill Moyers (Public Affairs Television) [schnur_141], (VHS) (Box 9)
  - Frontline (documentary re: Vietnam) 06/01/1985 [schnur_070], (Umatic) (Box 5)
  - Frontline: Russia: Love it or Leave it (Episode #403) [schnur_079], (Umatic) (Box 5)
  - Frontline: Sue the Doctor (Episode #402) 11/28/1986 [schnur_076], (Umatic) (Box 5)
  - Frontline: Abortion Clinic 01/30/1984 [schnur_071], (Umatic) (Box 5)
  - Frontline: Crisis in Zimbabwe (Episode #311) 04/25/1983 [schnur_069], (Umatic) (Box 5)
  - Frontline: Give Me that Big Time Religion (Episode # 204) 02/13/1984 [schnur_072], (Umatic) (Box 5)
  - Frontline: Hostage in Iran (Episode #401) (1 of 2) 01/21/1986 [schnur_075], (Umatic) (Box 5)
  - Frontline: Hostage in Iran (Episode #401) (2 of 2) 01/21/1986 [schnur_074], (Umatic) (Box 5)
  - Frontline: The Politics of Greed 06/03/1987 [schnur_077], (Umatic) (Box 5)
  - Frontline: The Struggle for Bermingham 04/02/1984 [schnur_073], (Umatic) (Box 5)
  - Frontline: The Trouble with Baseball (Episode #1115) 04/06/1993 [schnur_078], (VHS) (Box 5)
  - Good Morning America 4/7/1986: Kent State Memorial 04/07/1986 [schnur_080], (Umatic) (Box 5)
  - Guns: A Day in the Death of America (HBO) [schnur_082], (VHS) (Box 5)
  - Hank Aaron: Chasing the Dream (TBS) [schnur_151], (VHS) (Box 10)
  - High School Stories (Wisconsin Public TV and PBS) [schnur_136], (VHS) (Box 9)
  - High Schools (Carnegie Foundation for the Advancement of Teaching) [schnur_019], (Umatic) (Box 2)
  - History: 1949-1956 (general TV history) (WTVJ) [schnur_180], (Umatic) (Box 11)
  - History: 1950's (general TV history) (WTVJ) [schnur_181], (Umatic) (Box 11)
  - History: 1957-1959 (general TV history) (WTVJ) [schnur_182], (Umatic) (Box 11)
  - Holocaust Survivors 6/16/81 (WNET) 06/16/1981 [schnur_186], (Umatic) (Box 12)
  - Holocaust Survivors 6/17/81 (WNET) 06/17/1981 [schnur_187], (Umatic) (Box 12)
  - House Telecommunications Sub-committee Hearing on TV Violence (CBS) 05/26/1985 [schnur_050], (Umatic) (Box 4)
  - Huntley-Brinkley Report c.1956 (NBC) 05/09/1985 [schnur_119], (Umatic) (Box 8)
  - Iceman Tapes (HBO) [schnur_084], (VHS) (Box 6)
  - Illinois Power Co. Reply to 60 Minutes 11/05/1979 [schnur_092], (Umatic) (Box 6)
  - Innovation: Return to the Sea (WNET) [schnur_091], (Umatic) (Box 6)
  - Inside Russia (Metromedia TV) [schnur_112], (Umatic) (Box 7)
  - Inside Story: ARD Composite: Sex on Cable (2/83), Bounty Hunter (4/17/83), Hunger (5/12/82),100th Anniversary of the Brooklyn Bridge (5/25/83), Auslandsshow, 2nd Part (11/19/83), Queens Auslands Reporter (5/15/82) [schnur_095], (Umatic) (Box 6)
  - Inside Story: Christine Ockrent - Poland 01/22/1982 [schnur_093], (Umatic) (Box 6)
  - Inside Story: Secretaries of State [schnur_098], (Umatic) (Box 6)
  - Inside Story: Soviet Shows Excerpt Reel: Dateline Moscow, Inside the USSR, Soviet Children: the Privileged Class [schnur_099], (Umatic) (Box 6)
  - Inside Story: The Journal (Part I) 12/26/1984 [schnur_096], (Umatic) (Box 6)
  - International News 1962 (Universal) 05/15/1985 [schnur_153], (Umatic) (Box 10)
  - JFK Assassination (ABC 11/21/83, NBC 11/22/1983), Richard Allen Controversy (ABC 12/1/81, NBC 12/23/81) [schnur_066], (Umatic) (Box 5)
  - JFK with Peter Jennings (Reel 2) (ABC) 11/16/1983 [schnur_009], (Umatic) (Box 1)
  - JFK's First Press Conference (CBS) 01/25/1961 [schnur_024], (Umatic) (Box 2)
  - Jim Babb (Episode #102) (Part II) (Astronaut Obits) 04/02/1982 [schnur_188], (Umatic) (Box 12)
  - Journey of the African American Athlete (HBO) (Parts 1 and 2) [schnur_086], (VHS) (Box 6)
  - Kennedy's (Parts l-IV) [schnur_212], (VHS) (Box 13)
  - Kent State Shootings: 15 Years Later (WSY-TV Center) [schnur_177], (Umatic) (Box 11)
  - Kent State: May 1970 (E.G. Marshal, Narrator) (Kent State Audio Visual Services) [schnur_102], (Umatic) (Box 7)
  - Kuralt - On the Road, Moyers - Our Times (CBS) 08/23/1983 [schnur_057], (Umatic) (Box 4)
  - Last Days of Marilyn Monroe (1 of 2) 11/26/1985 [schnur_194], (Umatic) (Box 12)
  - Last Days of Marilyn Monroe (2 of 2) 11/26/1985 [schnur_195], (Umatic) (Box 12)
  - MacNeiI/Lehrer 2/10/1988 (racism on the college campus - last piece) 02/10/1988 [schnur_107], (Umatic) (Box 7)
  - MacNeiI/Lehrer 2/12/1986 (Dartmouth Review-conservatism) 02/12/1986 [schnur_106], (Umatic-SP) (Box 7)
  - Making of Nightline (ABC) 06/05/1985 [schnur_012], (Umatic) (Box 1)
  - Making of The Wizard of Oz (MGM/Turner Entertainment) 03/12/1987 [schnur_113], (Umatic) (Box 7)
  - Mannheim Documentary (SDR version) [schnur_207], (Umatic) (Box 13)
  - March on Washington Special (WNET) 08/29/1983 [schnur_173], (Umatic) (Box 11)
  - Meet the Press 4/28/1985: Marvin Kalb and Roger Mudd 04/28/1985 [schnur_108], (Umatic) (Box 7)
  - Merrow Report: Caught in the Crossfire [schnur_109], (VHS) (Box 7)
  - Merrow Report: Promises, Promises [schnur_110], (VHS) (Box 7)
  - Metroline Homeless 04/05/1988 [schnur_111], (Umatic) (Box 7)
  - Mind, The: Language (WNET) 05/06/1988 [schnur_175], (Umatic) (Box 11)
  - Mind, The: Thinking (WNET) 05/05/1988 [schnur_174], (Umatic) (Box 11)
  - MLK Speech "I have a dream" (8/28/63), Oswald Shooting, Nixon Resignation and Departure (8/9/74), Doug Edwards - Studio, Vietnam War "“ various from 4/29/75 special (CBS) [schnur_031], (Umatic) (Box 2)
  - Moonshadows (footage of conservatives at U.C. Berkeley) (KQED) 04/11/1981 [schnur_103], (Umatic) (Box 7)
  - Movietone News: "Russian scenes?" [schnur_140], (Umatic) (Box 9)
  - Movietone News: Battle of Stalingrad and Assorted WWII [schnur_115], (Umatic) (Box 7)
  - Movietone News: End of WWII, (Leningrad defense), Holland, Aerials of Bombing Mission, South Pacific, North Africa, Russia, Advance of German Troops, Russian Refugees [schnur_116], (Umatic) (Box 7)
  - Murder One (dub) [schnur_204], (Umatic) (Box 13)
  - NBC Evening News 5/18/1981: News Story on Public Housing 05/18/1981 [schnur_120], (Umatic) (Box 8)
  - NBC White Paper Vietnam: Lessons of a Lost War 04/27/1985 [schnur_121], (Umatic) (Box 8)
  - New Back Alleys (abortion) (ABC) 12/18/1978 [schnur_005], (Umatic-SP) (Box 1)
  - News at Eleven ("Jane Fonda" written on tape) 04/02/1986 [schnur_196], (Umatic) (Box 12)
  - News on Public Housing (John Johnson Reports) (WABC) 11/10/1982 [schnur_168], (Umatic) (Box 11)
  - Newton Minnow Addresses, National Association of Broadcasters (CBS) [schnur_061], (Umatic) (Box 4)
  - Nightline 11/24/1988: "Homeless" (off air copy) 11/24/1988 [schnur_126], (Umatic) (Box 8)
  - Nightline 4/25/1985: Ted Koppel in Vietnam 04/25/1985 [schnur_010], (Umatic) (Box 1)
  - Nightline 4/29/1985: Ted Koppel in Ho-Chi-Minh City (Part I) 04/29/1985 [schnur_122], (Umatic) (Box 8)
  - Nightline 4/29/1985: Ted Koppel in Ho-Chi-Minh City (Part II) 04/29/1985 [schnur_216], (Umatic) (Box 8)
  - Nightline 5/3/1985: Campus Activism Now and Then: Brown, Kent State, Stanford 05/03/1985 [schnur_123], (Umatic) (Box 8)
  - Nightline 6/3/1986: Rose Bird 06/03/1986 [schnur_125], (Umatic) (Box 8)
  - Nightline 6/3/1986: Rose Bird (master) 06/03/1986 [schnur_124], (Umatic) (Box 8)
  - Nightly Business Report 2/28/1983 (WPBT) 02/28/1983 [schnur_176], (Umatic) (Box 11)
  - Nixon/Cambodia, Women's Day March, Nixon Press Conference, Columbia Demonstrations (CBS) 04/30/1970 [schnur_039], (Umatic) (Box 3)
  - Not Necessarily the Year in Review (HBO) 12/12/1983 [schnur_081], (Umatic) (Box 5)
  - NOVA/Frontline: Visions of "Star Wars" (1 of 2) 04/22/1986 [schnur_128], (Umatic) (Box 8)
  - NOVA/Frontline: Visions of "Star Wars" (2 of 2) 04/22/1986 [schnur_129], (Umatic) (Box 8)
  - NOVA: Can Science Build the Perfect Athlete? [schnur_127], (VHS) (Box 8)
  - On the Record (Episode #101) 10/27/1985 [schnur_193], (Umatic) (Box 12)
  - Pearl Harbor (Wolpor) (A&E) [schnur_001], (VHS) (Box 1)
  - Portrait of America: Arkansas (TBS) 03/03/1985 [schnur_150], (Umatic) (Box 10)
  - Portrait of America: Arkansas (TBS) 03/03/1985 [schnur_152], (Umatic) (Box 10)
  - Portrait of America: Connecticut (TBS) 03/21/1984 [schnur_147], (Umatic) (Box 9)
  - Portrait of America: Idaho (TBS) 05/01/1984 [schnur_148], (Umatic) (Box 9)
  - Portrait of America: Louisiana (TBS) 06/26/1984 [schnur_149], (Umatic) (Box 9)
  - Portrait of America: Oregon (TBS) 03/12/1984 [schnur_146], (Umatic) (Box 9)
  - Rebels With a Cause: The Story of the American Football League (HBO) [schnur_085], (VHS) (Box 6)
  - Rebirth at Mannheim (The Press and Public Project) [schnur_138], (Umatic) (Box 9)
  - Renaissance Series (Part I) [schnur_205], (VHS) (Box 13)
  - Reuven Frank Interview (Reel #2) ("Graphics") 04/02/1982 [schnur_094], (Umatic-SP) (Box 6)
  - RFK Assassination (6/5/68), Berkeley Demonstration (5/19-5/20/69), Vietnam War: Hamburger Hill (5/21/69), Apollo II Moon walk (CBS) [schnur_037], (Umatic) (Box 3)
  - Rilly Sol Estes (CBS) 06/14/1962 [schnur_029], (Umatic) (Box 2)
  - Robert Toth (6/13-6/14/77), Breshnev/Kosygin (12/10/64-2/65), Krushev pix (10/20/64), Moscow transition (10/19/64), Krushev house (10/30/64), Prague Invasion (1968) ("Grindberg pulls") (ABC) [schnur_007], (Umatic) (Box 1)
  - Roger Mudd and Dan Rather 1965 ("Afghanistan") (CBS) 05/18/1985 [schnur_032], (Umatic) (Box 2)
  - Sacrifice at Pearl Harbor (Part 1) (VHS bump-up) [schnur_206], (Umatic) (Box 13)
  - Samantha Smith Goes to Washington: Campaign '84 (1 of 2) (KTLA) 02/14/1984 [schnur_104], (Umatic) (Box 7)
  - Samantha Smith Goes to Washington: Campaign '84 (2 of 2) (KTLA) 02/14/1984 [schnur_105], (Umatic) (Box 7)
  - Secret Intelligence (Part I) 10/22/1991 [schnur_197], (Umatic) (Box 12)
  - Secretaries in Conference (1985) 06/07/1985 [schnur_192], (Umatic) (Box 12)
  - Secretaries of State in Conference (1/4/1984) 04/02/1984 [schnur_191], (Umatic) (Box 12)
  - Seventies American Dream/American Nightmare (Part 1) (CBS) 12/30/1979 [schnur_045], (Umatic) (Box 3)
  - Seventies American Dream/American Nightmare (Part 2) (CBS) 12/30/1979 [schnur_046], (Umatic) (Box 3)
  - Silent Minority (WHA-TV Madison, Wisconsin) 03/01/1977 [schnur_064], (Umatic) (Box 4)
  - South Florida Reaction to Missile Crisis c.1962 (WTVJ) 05/15/1985 [schnur_179], (Umatic) (Box 11)
  - Soviet Children [schnur_208], (Umatic) (Box 13)
  - Soviet Women (Danish Title: Sovjetkvinder) (Danmark Radio Export) [schnur_065], (Umatic) (Box 4)
  - Soviet Women (Danish Title: Sovjetkvinder) (Danmark Radio Export) [schnur_209], (Umatic) (Box 13)
  - Soviets Human Rights (The Press and Public Project) 02/28/1983 [schnur_139], (Umatic) (Box 9)
  - Spark Among the Ashes: A Bar Mitzvah in Poland (Oren Rudophsky) [schnur_210], (Umatic) (Box 13)
  - Speech of President John F. Kennedy 10/22/1962 10/22/1962 [schnur_184], (Umatic-SP) (Box 12)
  - Story of a People: "Who is this Blackman?" (Syndicate Productions) 02/11/1988 [schnur_144], (Umatic) (Box 9)
  - Sunday Morning: Rochfort getting Medal of Honor with Costello and Lay (Hunt for Pearl Harbor Files) [schnur_087], (Umatic) (Box 6)
  - Telestar Transmission (CBS) 07/24/1962 [schnur_030], (Umatic-SP) (Box 2)
  - Television's Vietnam: The Real Story (Accuracy in Media) [schnur_014], (Umatic) (Box 1)
  - This is Edward R. Murrow (CBS) 04/03/1965 [schnur_034], (Umatic) (Box 3)
  - This Week with David Brinkley 3/20/83 (ABC) 03/20/1983 [schnur_008], (Umatic) (Box 1)
  - Two Roger Mudd Stories (CBS) 05/18/1985 [schnur_033], (Umatic) (Box 3)
  - U.S./Soviet Relations: The First 50 (PBS) 02/24/1984 [schnur_135], (Umatic) (Box 9)
  - Underwater video footage of USS Arizona and USS Utah (National Park Service) 10/23/1991 [schnur_118], (Umatic) (Box 8)
  - USA: A Television History: Mr. Wilson and the Great War (SCETV) 09/28/1984 [schnur_142], (Umatic) (Box 9)
  - Vietnam Follow-up (after last episode of reruns) (WETA) 09/20/1984 [schnur_170], (Umatic) (Box 11)
  - Vietnam: 10,000 Day War: Tet! (CBC) [schnur_020], (Umatic) (Box 2)
  - Vietnam: 10,000 Day War: The Trial (CBC) [schnur_021], (Umatic) (Box 2)
  - Vietnam: 10,000 Day War: Westy's War (Episode # 17) (CBC) [schnur_022], (Umatic) (Box 2)
  - Vietnam: A Television History: Roots of a War (Episode #101) 02/19/1985 [schnur_154], (Umatic) (Box 10)
  - Vietnam: A Television History: Roots of a War (Episode #101) 02/19/1985 [schnur_155], (Umatic) (Box 10)
  - Vietnam: A Television History: The First Vietnam War (Episode #102) 02/19/1985 [schnur_156], (Umatic) (Box 10)
  - Vietnam: A Television History: America's Mandarin (Episode #103) 02/19/1985 [schnur_157], (Umatic) (Box 10)
  - Vietnam: A Television History: LBJ Goes to War (Episode #104) 02/19/1985 [schnur_158], (Umatic) (Box 10)
  - Vietnam: A Television History: America Takes Charge (Episode #105) 02/19/1985 [schnur_159], (Umatic) (Box 10)
  - Vietnam: A Television History: America's Enemy (Episode #106) 02/19/1985 [schnur_160], (Umatic) (Box 10)
  - Vietnam: A Television History: Tet 1968 (Episode #107) 02/19/1985 [schnur_161], (Umatic) (Box 10)
  - Vietnam: A Television History: Vietnamizing the War (Episode #108) 02/19/1985 [schnur_162], (Umatic) (Box 10)
  - Vietnam: A Television History: Cambodia and Laos (Episode #109) 02/19/1985 [schnur_163], (Umatic) (Box 10)
  - Vietnam: A Television History: Peace is at Hand (Episode #110) 02/19/1985 [schnur_164], (Umatic) (Box 10)
  - Vietnam: A Television History: The End of the Tunnel (Episode #112) 02/19/1985 [schnur_165], (Umatic) (Box 10)
  - Vietnam: A Television History: Legacies (Episode #113) 02/19/1985 [schnur_166], (Umatic) (Box 10)
  - WABC Evening News 9/17/1981 (Where were you in '65) 09/17/1981 [schnur_167], (Umatic) (Box 11)
  - WCBS Views the Press (12/10/61) (CBS) 12/10/1961 [schnur_026], (Umatic) (Box 2)
  - WCBS Views the Press (4/24/61 and 6/26/61) (CBS) 05/14/1985 [schnur_025], (Umatic) (Box 2)
  - West 57th Street (Premier Show) 08/13/1985 [schnur_169], (Umatic) (Box 11)
  - WLBT News (6PM and 10PM Reports) [schnur_172], (Umatic) (Box 11)